Previously on "The 100"...
CLARKE: Something's coming,
a wave of radiation that'll
kill everything in its path.
JAHA: There might be a fallout shelter.
ROAN: A final Conclave,
and whoever wins gets the bunker.
OCTAVIA: Skaikru will
not take the bunker alone.
We will share it. We are one clan.
BELLAMY: We're not leaving you behind.
There's no time to get back.
We're not going back. We're going up.
RAVEN: Once the tablet is connected,
the dish will align itself with the Ark.
VOICE: Dish aligned.
RAVEN: It's gonna take
you a good 10 minutes
to get back from the tower
and down to the cockpit,
or you will be left behind.
VOICE: 3, 2, 1.
May we meet again.
RAVEN: She did it. She saved us again.
[GASPING]
- _
- [WIND BLOWING]
[PANTING]
210 miles to Polis.
At least I don't have to swim.
You got this.
[THUMP THUMP]
[EXPLOSIONS]
[ENGINE STOPS]
[THUD]
[PANTING]
[RUMBLING]
I'm here!
I'm here! Mom!
[WIND WHISTLING]
[RUMBLING]
No.
[PANTING]
CLARKE, VOICE-OVER: Where
was I? Oh, right. Polis.
Up until that moment,
I believed I'd live
in the bunker with the
others, with my mom.
I can't bear the thought
of leaving her down there,
but the hard truth is,
I could dig for years
and never reach that door.
I've been by myself now for two months,
but this is the first time I feel alone.
It's like we were never here.
Maybe we never should have been.
How the hell am I gonna make it 5 years?
CLARKE, VOICE-OVER: I
came to Arkadia looking
for food or water,
but all I found were ghosts.
[SOBS]
[SNIFFLES]
[SOBBING]
CLARKE, VOICE-OVER: Part
of me thinks that Jasper
had the right idea.
What's the point if all there
is is pain and suffering?
[CHUCKLES]
Real cheerful, Clarke.
I'm sorry. Ignore me, ok? I
haven't had water in two days.
I need to find some soon,
or I don't think I'm gonna...
[STATIC]
Anyway...
[CLEARS THROAT]
I doubt you can hear me on
this piece-of-crap radio...
But in case this is the
last time I get to do this,
I just want to say...
Please don't feel bad
about leaving me here.
You did what you had to do.
I'm proud of you.
[CHURCHES' "SCIENCE/VISIONS" PLAYING]
[STATIC]
LAUREN MAYBERRY: ♪ Breathe ♪
♪ Don't speak ♪
♪ It's leaving your body now ♪
CHURCHES: ♪ I, I ♪
♪ Hear, hear ♪
♪ Your, your breathing ♪
MAYBERRY: ♪ Light by day ♪
♪ A shadow resides by night ♪
CHURCHES: ♪ Feel, feel ♪
♪ You, you leaving ♪
[THUNDER]
[RAIN FALLING]
Thank you.
[CHUCKLES]
[RON GALLO'S "YOUNG LADY,"
YOU'RE SCARING ME" PLAYING]
GALLO: Whoo!
♪ Your cavern eyes are preying ♪
♪ Your scarlet lips half-saying ♪
♪ A sales pitch for the
circus in your mind ♪
♪ Young lady, you're scaring me ♪
[RUMBLING]
[WIND ROARING]
The solar panels.
Damn it.
[GASPING]
[COUGHS]
[ENGINE CRANKS]
You think you can kill me?
Have at it.
[WIND WHISTLING]
[GASPS]
[PANTING]
Wait. Show me where you live.
Yes. Take me to your home.
[PANTING]
No.
I'm done! Do you hear me?
I've lost everything!
I lost my friends, my father, my mother!
I've got nothing left!
[SOBBING]
[SNIFFLES]
[BIRD SQUAWKS]
[SQUAWK]
Hey!
[PANTING]
Thank you.
[SQUAWK]
CLARKE, VOICE-OVER: I
used to think that life
was about more than just surviving,
but I'm not sure anymore.
Animals don't feel
guilty when they kill.
They just do it. They
kill, or they get killed.
I tell myself that every
life I took was for a reason,
but the truth is, the
other side had reasons, too.
The Grounders, the Mountain
Men, even A.L.I.E...
Their reasons to want us
dead were the same as ours.
It was us or them,
kill or be killed, simple as that.
So what now?
What becomes of the Commander of Death
when there's no one left to kill?
I guess we'll find out
because my fight is over.
The question is, who am I now?
_
Wait till you see this place.
It's like the death wave
jumped over the entire valley.
Unfortunately, the radiation didn't.
I've lost track of how
many bodies we've burned
since reaching the ground.
God, this would be so much
easier if I knew you were alive,
if I knew I was gonna see you again.
Positive thoughts, Clarke.
It's been 58 days.
By now, Monty should have
the algae farm producing.
Hope bad does it suck?
No offense, Monty.
[STATIC]
And I found berries,
a whole field of them.
They're not very sweet,
but they're beautiful.
I think that's what they
used to make the paint for...
Wait. It's ok.
It's ok. Wait.
_
Hey, it's ok.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Wait.
Are you alone?
Are there others?
_
It's ok.
So you can...
_
No.
Hey!
[MOANING]
No.
[PANTING]
No. No. No.
_
[PANTING]
Last two people on Earth,
one of them happens to
be the child from Hell.
[WINCES]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
_
[ROVER APPROACHING]
[ENGINE STOPS]
[DOOR OPENS]
CLARKE: Hey, wash up.
It's time for supper.
Look. The berries are ripe.
That's nice. Come on.
I caught. You cook.
Clarke, you promised.
Last season, there weren't enough,
but this year, they're everywhere.
Please?
I'll cook for a week and clean up.
Two weeks.
Deal. Come on. I'll drive.
_
English, Madi.
I'm just saying, Skairipa's a beast.
Of course she'd win the Conclave.
Don't worry.
She'll get them out of that bunker.
I know she will.
I'm sorry they left without you.
Well, I'm not
because if I was with them,
I never would have met you.
What about them?
Do you think they'll come back, too?
[RUMBLING]
[RAVEN AND ECHO GRUNTING]
[THUD]
[GRUNTING CONTINUES]
Soup's on.
Ha ha! Yes! Finally.
Oh, come on. I let you
win so we could eat.
This isn't eating. It's surviving.
Hey, the new and improved triple-G
tastes better, and you know it.
Triple-G?
He calls this one Green's green goop.
Better name, too.
And if by better, you mean doesn't want
to make you violently hurl,
then, yeah, it's an improvement.
Speaking of green, how's Eden?
Still just a dot. Emori, take a break.
RAVEN: I don't know
why you waste your time.
I told you, atmospheric radiation
blocks radio signals.
They're down there. We
just can't hear them.
We waste our time so they know
there's a place they can live.
Ground radiation has been
survivable for a year.
They can live everywhere.
I think we can all
agree that green is good.
Yes. He is...
But this stuff still sucks.
[COUGHS]
Ok. Tomorrow I'll try again
to boost the signal from the antenna.
EMORI: Shotgun. Ha ha! Space walk. Yes.
RAVEN: I know the feeling,
but I need an assistant
who actually listens when
I tell her to come in.
I will do everything you say, I promise,
no fun of any kind.
Or we could just figure out
a way to get to the ground,
and we could tell them
about Eden ourselves.
Bellamy, she worked on the
fuel problem all morning.
6 years and 7 days.
HARPER: Hey, time violation.
Dishes, latrine, or Murphy? You choose.
I'm sorry.
We said we wouldn't talk about it,
and I know that you're doing
everything that you can.
- Seconds?
- Yeah, right.
I choose Murphy.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SIGHS]
I'd have gone with latrines.
This is my side of the ship,
remember? What's the matter?
You wanted me to train,
right, so let's do it.
[BOTH PANTING]
All right, but I win, you
come back to the group.
No deal.
You have too many rules.
Besides, there's no one
to disappoint over here.
Murphy...
[COUGHS]
- That's a good punch.
- Yeah?
Now, if you shift your weight
when you throw it, might actually hurt.
You know what I think your problem is?
This should be good.
You like being a hero,
except up here, there are no heroes.
You're afraid you'd
become worthless again.
You're not worthless, Murphy.
Wait, wait. Bellamy, look. Oh!
Say you're not worthless,
and I'll let you go.
Not kidding! Will you look? Look!
Let's go.
Come on.
MURPHY: It's been 2 1/2 hours.
Why, exactly, are we
sitting here in the dark?
We should light up the ring,
let them know we're here.
Quiet, Murphy.
First, we find out who they are,
and then we ask them for help.
- Raven?
- Nothing.
Radio sounds. Their
comms might be disabled.
Or the ship could be unmanned.
MURPHY: Or it's manned
by aliens who prefer
anal probes to radios.
Doesn't really matter as long as they
get us down to the ground.
I'm turning on the lights.
You know what? That's enough.
We make decisions as a team here,
even if we can't stand
the sight of each other.
Look. All I'm saying is,
it wasn't there yesterday.
Now it's in geosynchronous orbit,
which means someone is
piloting it, correct?
HARPER: It could be an AI.
MURPHY: I prefer the aliens.
Something's happening.
A second ship.
Look.
That must be a transport.
It's headed for the ground.
Emori, fire up the radio.
Now she wants to talk.
Mayday, mayday.
I am hailing the drop ship
now on re-entry to earth.
We are stranded aboard the
space station to your west.
Please respond.
MURPHY: Great.
Looks like we just lost our last chance
to get back to the ground.
Mayday, mayday.
I am calling the drop ship
now on re-entry to Earth.
Madi, pack up the Rover.
Get it out of sight and load the guns.
- All of them?
- All of them.
Who are they? Why are you so scared?
I will not let anything happen to you.
Do you understand?
Well, maybe they're friendly.
Maybe.
Look. Until I figure this out,
I want you to hide in your secret spot.
No. Clarke...
This is not up for discussion, Madi.
The Flamekeeper scouts
never found you there.
Neither will they.
[EXHALES]
Promise me you'll stay in the hole.
What about you?
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Now promise me.
I promise.
Here.
If you shoot, they'll hear you.
I'll make sure it's my only choice.
Go.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[WHOOSH]
All clear.
So much for the meek
inheriting the earth.
Whatever took out the rest of the world
must have missed this spot.
You think?
You were right.
Spending extra time in
orbit to find this place
was a good call.
Now see if you can figure
out what the hell happened
to our planet while we were asleep.
On it.
Uh, nonviolent offenders with me?
Yeah, both of them.
Smart.
Give him that.
Relax, McCreary.
You're still my favorite mass murderer.
Sweep the village door to door,
then the woods.
Let's find out what
we're dealing with here.
[GUNSHOT]
Out! Come on. Now!
MAN: What the hell is this?
Little bitch shot me.
MAN: Aw, come on, man.
You gonna shoot a kid?
Why not?
For starters, because she's a kid.
How about I put one in your leg
so you know how it feels?
[GUNSHOT]
Clarke!
[GAGGING]
[GUNSHOT]
[COUGHING]
Hey, it's ok.
[COUGHING CONTINUES]
Wait. He tried to help me.
I think he might be a good guy.
There are no good guys.
Jenson, Baines, we heard two more
gunshots in your direction.
Report.
What's it mean?
MAN: Fan out. Now.
Means we're not alone.
Monty, come on. Pack your things.
I don't think we should do this.
Look. I know it's a risk,
but they have a transport,
which means they carry fuel.
We can do this.
What if it's the wrong fuel?
We'll need to burn most
of what we have left
just to dock, which
means we won't have enough
to get back here to the place
where we've been safe
for the last 6 years.
We leave, we can't come back.
Is that really a risk
you're willing to take?
Yes. It is.
What if they won't let us dock?
What's this really about?
Hey, talk to me.
I killed my mother.
I let my best friend kill himself.
Oh, it wasn't your fault, Monty.
I could have done more.
I don't want to be that person again.
Oh...
You are strong, Monty.
That's one of the
reasons why I love you.
No one should have to be that strong.
EMORI: Remember, radio me when John gets
to the hangar bay so I can go get my...
Saved you the trouble.
Thanks.
I'll start the preflight check.
Well, you blew a good thing.
Thanks for the empathy.
Sorry. Just, having a roommate
for the last 6 months
because she made you
feel inadequate has got me feeling
a little cranky.
Hmm. Here I was, thinking it was
because you couldn't get
us back down to the ground.
That's the thing they don't tell you
about happily ever after...
Harder than it looks.
Hmm, you know what this is?
It's a cockroach playing the violin.
- Oh.
- Going the wrong way.
Final sweep. Right behind you.
BELLAMY: Wouldn't it be
easier just to step outside?
[CHUCKLES]
What are we gonna be now, Bellamy?
Hey... look.
Nothing is gonna change on the ground.
I wish that were true.
Oh, I know it is.
We've kept each other alive,
all of us.
We're family, and
nothing can change that.
I'm still banished.
What if Octavia tries...
- No. She won't.
- You do remember,
I almost killed your sister.
You're right. You're screwed.
[CHUCKLES]
My sister will understand, you know,
and if she's ok and alive and...
Shh...
She's ok.
Then she'll forgive you, too.
Bellamy, it took you 3 years.
I'm more stubborn than her.
- Ha ha!
- Good.
Trust me, whatever we
run into down there,
Octavia will be the
least of our worries.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
Yah!
[CHEERING]
Synced and corrected by Octavia
- www.addic7ed.com -